Attempting to get back into school

Day 00421: Sunday, 2016 May 01

Ronsor's been missing for quite a while now. He said that he was shutting down his IRC server to switch daemons, but then his IRC server never came back up. I assumed that he'd borked his onion address in some way, but I asked around in #Volatile. Wowaname's also been unable to connect, but she also said that she's been using the onion address. I took a look at Ronsor's clearnet website though, and that's missing as well, as is his Minetest server. Soon after making my inquiry on #Volatile, Ronsor showed up. I suspect that wowaname has some alternate communication channel with Ronsor. Ronsor says that he's fixed his server, but I still cannot see his website or connect to his IRC server, and now he's disappeared again.

Our landlords want to put this house on the market soon, so a real estate agent is going to be coming into our home at some point in the near future. We only have about two months longer on our lease, so we don't have a whole lot of time to move out, either.

I checked on the temp agency's job board again and it doesn't look like there are any new options.

I looked into University of [REDACTED], which claims to be the world's first tuition-free university. To call them tuition-free is a bit misleading though. They do charge fees, they just don't call it "tuition". First, there's the non-refundable $50 USD application fee. Just to attempt to get admitted, you need to pay this, and if they decline your application, you don't even get to ever learn why. Second, you don't have to pay for the courses themselves, but for the courses to count for anything, you have to pay for an exam at the end of each course. That means that the courses *do* cost, they just are labeling the fee as something other than "tuition". It sounds like the total cost for tests each year is $1000 USD. That's extremely inexpensive for college courses! It's still far from gratis though, and their word choice is misleading. I filled out the application as best as I could, but they ask for a telephone number. I tried to leave it blank, but they say that the information is incomplete so they cannot process it. I thought that that would be the end, but I filled it in with a sentence saying that I don't have telephone service and they accepted that. I fear that they will use this as a reason not to admit me and just take my $50 USD, but I'll have no way to know for sure if that was the reason that I was declined. I asked my mother for advice on this, and she didn't really have a clear answer. She did want to know where Cyrus learned about the school though and if it was the school that he's planning to attend. As it turns out, he learned about the school in a video shown in one of his high school classes, but he's not attending that university as they don't offer the major that he's interested in. They also require proof that I've completed high school. I apologize, but that requirement leads us on a bit of a tangent.

When I graduated high school, my mother *insisted* that she get to hold onto my diploma "for a while". She specified no time frame and I was uncomfortable with this even at the time. However, I wasn't really in any position to argue. Today, I asked my mother for the diploma, as I needed to make a copy of it to send as proof of graduation. She's lost it though. She has no idea where it is. I now have no diploma. This makes me very angry. I can't let her know that though.

With no diploma, I tried to find information on getting my diploma replaced. I never did find a way to do that, but I did find something that will work for now: information on how to get official high school transcripts. This is suboptimal, as the transcripts reveal more personal information than the diploma, but they will have to do. The university's application deadline is May fifth, but I'm not going to make it in time. The high school requires that transcript requests be made via fax or post and requires that official transcripts also be sent via post. In addition to waiting for the mail in both directions, they say that it will take seven to ten business days to prepare the transcripts. If my mother hadn't taken and lost my diploma, I'd be set, but now I'll have to try for next semester instead. I'll send in my transcript request via post tomorrow. The form to request transcripts asks for a telephone number and a fax number. I've left both blank, but I'm not sure how they will react to the missing telephone number. Most people just assume that every other person on the planet has at least one telephone line and are perfectly comfortable giving out the number. They don't even consider the possibility that people might choose not to have telephone service, instead making themselves available via more flexible channels of communication instead. The form offers the option to get up to five official transcripts, up to five unofficial transcripts, and the immunization records of the student if the school system has them. I decided to get five official transcript copies, as having extras on hand will speed this sort of process later. I also chose to get one unofficial copy just so I can see what's on record. A second unofficial copy would be useless to me, as unofficial copies probably won't be accepted as proof of anything. I also chose to get a copy of my immunization records. They'll be beyond outdated by now, but I'd like to know what they have on file about me.

I've fine-tuned my email filters a bit now. It's nice not receiving as much spam or political mail directly in my inbox, but even social media mail and routine mail blocks out mail that should be seen right away. It used to be that I could be reached very easily via email, but that's not been the case over the last several months.

It's come to my attention that my plan to try to get that CD that Marc With a C sent me freed is a very bad plan. The fact is, it's a cover album. To make sense of that, I should explain my thoughts on music and the law. I'm not overly-knowledgeable about legal matters, so if you think that I'm wrong about something, I probably am. Do your own research, don't trust me. Anyway, I believe that most "freely-licensed" covers of nonfree songs are actually illegal. I highly doubt that the covering artist actually got permission to release a free version of the song, thus freeing the song itself (though not the original artist's original recording). However, it's not my job to look into it. The covering artist might have special permission that I don't know about. Otherwise, it's the covering artist that's taking the risk, not me. Likewise, I'm not into popular culture. Unless explicitly labeled as a cover song, I won't usually know that a cover song is a cover song. I don't have the time or energy to look into every song that an artist releases trying to figure out if it's a cover song. Even if I did look into each song, I could never prove that any given song wasn't a cover of some obscure song that I couldn't find. Lastly, and perhaps more importantly, I'm more concerned with the spirit of free music than I am with the law. I could probably pirate and remix almost any song that I wanted to without getting caught, especially if I distributed from an onion address that was hosted on a more reliable provider than my ISP (as my connection constantly goes down and correlations can be made between my onions because of it) and that didn't make any mention of me. My goal in supporting free music is to support free music artists and draw more attention to them. If they call their cover songs free, they are giving up any perceived rights that they had to legally fight those that would reuse their already-reused work. For me, that's enough. I choose not to listen to the original nonfree works, but if a covering artist slaps a CC BY-SA license on their cover of it, I won't try to avoid their version. That said, I shouldn't encourage artists to take this risk, nor should I try to get them to try to bargain with proprietary artists for permission to release free versions of the songs. Instead, I should try to get artists to release their own copyrighted works under free licenses. I can't try to free this cover CD.

Speaking of copyright, I stumbled upon a Wikipedia article explaining the copyright status of works produced by the United States government. I had thought that works created by my country's government were not subject to copyright, meaning that anything created by my government is in the public domain. However, it seems that this only applies on a national level. State governments are free to exercise or waive copyrights of their own works as they please. Wikipedia didn't mention Oregon on its list of the copyright status of works by various state governments and I can't find any information about the subject elsewhere. I had assumed that certain literature provided by Oregon was free, but it seems that it's probably not.

Vanessa, our mother, and I spent about half the day gathering bullet shells in the hills again. I point out plants fairly regularly in an attempt to look like I'm having a good time, but now my mother thinks that I might want to be a botanist. In truth, the plants are just more interesting than the dirt or the rocks, which are the main other things around. I need to try to dial it back a bit, I suppose.

There may be a solution to the fact that Links and Links2 are non-conformant Web browsers after all. With the \DOMDocument class in hand, I might be able to parse my XHTML-based journal entries and format them differently as plain text files. It's going to take effort and time, but I can make each XHTML tag change the plain text output in some way, if applicable. Unknown tags will cause an exception to be thrown just to make sure that I don't overlook something. Hyperlinks are going to be a pain to work with, but I think that they'll be manageable. I'll also need to find a way to set a maximum line length, which will be ignored by long URIs to avoid URIs from being broken. I'm not entirely sure what to do with <del/> and <ins/> tags though. At worst, I can have <del/> tags disappear from the plain text version of the page and have <ins/> tags render as regular text. Hopefully I'll find a better solution before I implement this. The important thing is that now this allows me to tackle a problem in a client that can't correctly interpret XHTML using plain text solutions. Almost any client should be able to render a plain text file without problem. The only potential issue that I see is that a client may be Markdown-enabled and mistakingly interpret all plain text files as Markdown. If a client cannot read XHTML files or plain text files correctly though, I'm not sure what else to try.

Before I launch myself into a large project like this, I need to finish include.d's release. I've completed one of the two remaining test scripts, so the release draws ever nearer. It shouldn't be too long before I can finish the final file and make the release.

Document modifications

On 2017-11-02, this journal page was modified in order to redact the name of the university and the link to their website.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Switching email clients (again)

Day 00422: Monday, 2016 May 02

Fearing that the high school might deny my transcript request based on my home address not matching the address on my photo ID, I made a copy of the change-of-address label sent to me by the DMV, cut it out, then copied my ID with the label copy applied. I biked down to the post office to get it mailed, so now all I can do as far as school is concerned is wait.

A while back, Chris Zabriskie gave me his albums that he released under the name Lo-Fi is Sci-Fi, but due to not coming through the usual channels, they are in MP3 format and without cover art. Today, I tracked down the cover art. I got it from the Free Music Archive, though I won't link to them due to being behind a CloudFlare CAPTCHA wall. The Lo-Fi is Sci-Fi albums and artist profile have been deleted from the website, but the individual tracks are still accessible. The cover art isn't linked to in any findable way, but DuckDuckGo found all four album covers when I searched for the cover of "O Great Queen Electric, What Do You Have Waiting for Me?". If someone reading this has FLAC files, I'm still looking for those. Unfortunately, Chris removed the Bandcamp page, so we can't just buy FLAC files there.

The name "Pinentry" has always been strange in my mind, though now I think that I know what it means: "PIN entry"; I found a page that calls it "pin-entry". Speaking of which, I managed to track down instructions for making Pinentry less annoying. In addition to making GnuPG remember passwords for a short time so that multiple files may be signed in one session, these instructions prevent Pinentry from hogging focus and preventing one from typing in other applications. this is exceedingly helpful if you need to type your password to unlock a password database and retrieve a password to unlock your PGP key.

LXDE requires a lot of work just to get into a usable state. Once there though, it seems to be a lot nicer than other desktops. Xfce on the other hand is very nice and configured pretty well by default, but it's impossible to configure it to behave reasonably in some ways. If LXDE had a reasonable default configuration, I could actually recommend it to people, but as it is, I can't really do that. I can't recommend software that takes a lot of time and research; that just wouldn't be a nice thing for me to do.

My primary election ballot came by post today. I should make sure to have it filled out and submitted by the sixteenth of this month. It's due by the seventeenth, but I don't have the full day to submit it both because it's due earlier in the day and because the public library (the nearest ballot drop box) isn't open all day. I need to research the candidates for most offices, I don't know anything about them. All that I currently know is that I need to vote against Clinton for the presidential nomination.

I decided to try to contact the Copperhead team to see if they use binary blobs in their operating system. However, their PGP key doesn't contain the email address that I needed to write to, so Evolution refused to encrypt the email. I needed to set up a more flexible mail client. I looked into Icedove, which I've used in the past, but wasn't able to meet my needs before. Now, however, in addition to the availability of a plugin to provide PGP support, I found a plugin to provide CardDAV support. After setting up the connection to the server, I realized that I'd forgotten to set the client up to use Tor, much to my frustration. Migrating my old local email database to the new email client was no walk in the park either. I found some instructions for making the switch, bu they didn't work. I finally found some newer information, and as it turns out, Evolution used to use the same database format as Icedove, but Evolution has been updated to use a newer format that uses multiple smaller files instead of one large one. This seems like a better format to me just because the emails are easier to separate and if one is damaged, the rest could be fine. However, as Icedove is still using the older format, the email database needed to be converted before it could be imported. After much frustration, I finally found this script:

#!/usr/bin/env python 
# -*- coding: utf-8 -*-
"""
Frédéric Grosshans, 19 January 2012
Nathan R.
	Yergler, 6 June 2010

This file does not contain sufficient creative expression to invoke
assertion of copyright.
	No warranty is expressed or implied; use at
your own risk.

---

Uses Python's included mailbox library to convert mail archives from
maildir [http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maildir] to 
mbox [http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mbox] format, icluding subfolder.

See http://docs.python.org/library/mailbox.html#mailbox.Mailbox for 
full documentation on this library.

---

To run, save as md2mb.py and run:

$ python md2mb.py [maildir_path] [mbox_filename]

[maildir_path] should be the the path to the actual maildir (containing new, 
cur, tmp, and the subfolders, which are hidden directories with names like 
.subfolde.subsubfolder.subsubsbfolder);

[mbox_filename] will be newly created, as well as a [mbox_filename].sbd the 
directory.
"""

import mailbox
import sys
import email
import os

def maildir2mailbox(maildirname, mboxfilename):
    """
    slightly adapted from maildir2mbox.py, 
    Nathan R.
	Yergler, 6 June 2010
    http://yergler.net/blog/2010/06/06/batteries-included-or-maildir-to-mbox-again/


    """
    # open the existing maildir and the target mbox file
    maildir = mailbox.Maildir(maildirname, email.message_from_file)
    mbox = mailbox.mbox(mboxfilename)

    # lock the mbox
    mbox.lock()

    # iterate over messages in the maildir and add to the mbox
    for msg in maildir:
        mbox.add(msg)

    # close and unlock
    mbox.close()
    maildir.close()

#Creates the main mailbox
dirname=sys.argv[-2]
mboxname=sys.argv[-1]
print(dirname +' -> ' +mboxname)
mboxdirname=mboxname+'.sbd'
maildir2mailbox(dirname,mboxname)
if not os.path.exists(mboxdirname): os.makedirs(mboxdirname)

listofdirs=[dn for dn in os.walk(dirname).next()[1] if dn not in ['new', 'cur', 'tmp']]
for curfold in listofdirs:
    curlist=[mboxname]+curfold.split('.')
    curpath=os.path.join(*[dn+'.sbd' for dn in curlist if dn])
    if not os.path.exists(curpath): os.makedirs(curpath)
    print('| ' +curfold +' -> '+curpath[:-4])
    maildir2mailbox(os.path.join(dirname,curfold),curpath[:-4])

print('Done')

Using that script converted the database very painlessly, though locating the script in the first place wasn't easy.

With my email client set up, I sent my inquiry to the CopperheadOS team.

While waiting for a response, I also asked if anyone in #Replicant knew anything. I specifically mentioned the "optional Google service integration", and pab3 said that microG could be used to integrate Google services without including proprietary components. I don't know for sure that this is what's being used to provide the integration though, I only know that it's a possibility.

I should have finished the release of include.d today, but getting my email client set up took a lot of time. Maybe I'll get it done tomorrow.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

include.d version 0.0.1.3

Day 00423: Tuesday, 2016 May 03

The University of [REDACTED] wrote to me offering me the option of filling out a form saying that I'm having trouble getting proof of my completion of high school instead of providing said proof. I might be able to take that option, but their form isn't on their website and is on a website that maliciously discriminates against Tor users. I'll just continue to wait for the official documents to arrive and try to enroll for the term after this coming one.

I found that my new mail client leaks DNS queries just like my old one! Because of this, I can't connect to my onion-based CardDAV server. This is both a problem of privacy and one of practicality.

The Copperhead CEO wrote to me about my inquiry from yesterday. He says that yes, CopperheadOS makes use of proprietary software, specifically hardware drivers. That's very disappointing. At least we still have Replicant though, which has a strong commitment to freedom.

I wrote up the final test for include.d only to find that my /robots.txt file interpretation class always seems to say that accessing every part of a website is available to be crawled, regardless of the actual rules specified in the file. All this time, I thought that my spider was respecting /robots.txt files, but it hasn't been! I'm not sure how I didn't catch this before. Surely I did some sort of output testing when I was building the class. In any case, it's been fixed now, and include.d version 0.0.1.3 has been released!

I began work on the PHP class needed to convert my weblog entries into plain text files. I decided to take it in a slightly different direction than originally planned, and am making it function on entire XHTML files instead of just the fragments that are my actual entries. This way, it should work on any well-formed Web page, not just my own work (not that much of the Web actually uses well-formed documents). This might result in my upper navigation showing up in the plain text version of my entries, but that might not be a bad thing. Additionally, I've decided to use PHP's XML parser instead of the \DOMDocument class. This has the disadvantage that my code won't be able to handle any page that isn't well-wormed, even if it's perfectly-valid HTML, but the advantage that it'll be loads easier to write. I'm not really a fan of markup that isn't well-formed anyway, it's not my job to enable it. If someone wants to take the time to build an HTML to plain text converter, by all means, they should. I'm plenty happy only parsing valid XHTML pages though, especially as I only need to parse my own pages. My class isn't really meant to be unleashed on the Web anyway. It's built to take one format that's used for storage and convert it to another that's used for presentation. The fact that my storage format is identical to XHTML is only a feature of convenience.

There's a high probability that the next include.d update will only add this new class. The last update got to be a bit large, but it really only had one goal: fix up the output of a single existing function. All other additions made were either required in order to fix that function or were the result of more code being added before the main goal could be accomplished. The new output required several new classes be added to embody the data more precisely. This class is less ambitious, so the update should come quicker and have less changes.

My mother wants us to prepare for the upcoming move, but has given no specific instructions. I've already set aside a couple of boxes of stuff that I'll be trying to get rid of at our upcoming garage sale and my stuff is very consolidated. After all, I don't really have much living space. She did mention that the dishes need to be done though, so I suppose that I'll work on that, despite the fact that it's Cyrus' job, not mine.

Document modifications

On 2017-11-02, this journal page was modified in order to redact the name of the university and the link to their website.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Cyrus is being booted from our home

Day 00424: Wednesday, 2016 May 04

I made some progress in my class that converts XHTML files into plain text files, but I still have a long way to go. Lists are one thing that are in vital need of implementation. Without special instructions, lists are probably formatted as just blobs of text with all list items run together. I haven't tested this, but it seems like what my current instructions to the computer would do. Additionally, I need to make the navigation disappear from the plain text files, as it's just an ugly mess and as the links are unclickable, it's not even helpful to have the navigation displayed. I think that if I implement <nav/> tags in my XHTML, I can easily strip out the navigation in the plain text copy of the pages, but I'll need to look into how <nav/> tags are even used to make sure that I use them properly. I'll also need to make sure that everything within the <head/> tag that isn't within the <title/> tag is stripped out. It won't make a difference on my pages, but if embedded JavaScript or an embedded stylesheet is used, it should be stripped out. Then again, embedded JavaScript should be stripped from the body too, so I should also add parsing instructions that remove <script/> tags as well. Additionally, my XHTML page footer seems problematic. When rendered in text files, if comes through as:

W3C standards are important.
	This document conforms to the XHTML5
specification and uses a stylesheet that conforms the CSS
specification.

My plain text files do not conform to the XHTML specification and do not use any CSS. I'm not sure how to remove this footer, but I should look for a way when time allows. Lastly, I'm going to need to write some code to deal with the updating of plain text files on my website. My XHTML files aren't clearsigned because clearsigning XHTML invalidates it, so I use external signatures. Plain text files have no such problem, so they'll be clearsigned. Signatures seem to contain the signing time in some way though, so I can't sign files and check to see if they match the old files. I'll need to instead strip off the signatures, compare them to the new file contents, then if the two differ, sign the new contents and update the file.

It strikes me that this new PHP class works a bit like reverse Markdown. Instead of somehow making a plain text file somehow parsible, sacrificing the ability to use certain characters in the process and adding strange characters to the "plain text" version of a document where they don't belong, I can use actual markup with actual escape sequences where needed. This is what markup was *designed* for: to be parsed. If I want my output to be plain text, that makes no difference. Plain text on the other hand was not meant to be parsed. Any attempt to make plain text parsible will likely result in one of two cases: an essentially-new file format that's fairly readable while still clearly not being simple text in a file, such as the CSV format, or an utter abomination that makes trouble where there needn't be any, such as Markdown. If you want a file to be parsed by a machine, it's vital that you include escape sequences in your language, or at least use non-printing characters to provide the parsing instructions. Of course, non-printing characters make the file too difficult to work with. It can be argued that using provided escape sequences makes the document appear less readable without parsing, but it's far better than not having any escape sequences at all.

It has been brought to my attention that potentially-revealing server information has been accessible via https://authorednansyxlu.onion/server-status. The problem isn't that it reveals information about where I am, as I'm already on the clearnet, but that it reveals information about my other visitors and what parts of the website that they're looking at. With a bit of research, I found that the culprit was mod_status. Disabling that was as easy as deleting a particular configuration file and restarting Apache.

The GNOME team seem to be closer to to figuring out where their SNI bug is located in their code. They now believe that the bug is in glib-networking. They're slow to act, but at least they aren't trying to claim that the bug is a feature and justify keeping it in their code. If they get this bug fixed in time for the fix to make it into Debian 9, I'll be ecstatic. I'll hopefully have a variety of Web browsers using Qt or GTK+ that I can recommend to people.

Cyrus broke one of my pairs of headphones today. Unfortunately, that pair was of one of those uncommon headphone types that have a jack that fits in my mobile protector's stupidly-tiny jack opening without being such a low-quality pair that they aren't even worth using. It'll take quite a while to find a replacement for them.

Much of the day was spent cleaning dishes and counters, along with general house cleaning and working on job hunting and code in the in-between spaces. However, this wasn't good enough for my mother. She's having another of her bipolar fits, set off by Vanessa this time, and freaked out at all of us. She told me to get out, though she didn't seem to be serious, and of the three of us, I'm by far the one that she yelled at the least. She did get angry with me for continuing my job hunt, claiming that she'd told me that she wants me to stop looking for a job and work on getting us ready to move instead. She did say that she wanted help getting us ready to move, but I don't recall her saying anything about ceasing the job hunt. Her mind is so frayed that she often has a warped view of past events, so I'm almost certain that she said no such thing to me.

Cyrus took most of our mother's wrath today. She's behaving much like many divorced parents, trying to force Cyrus and Vanessa to choose one parent and abandon the other. Cyrus will do no such thing, so she's booting him from our household. At first, she was saying that he needed to be ready to leave for Springfield by the weekend and he'd need to transfer back to his old school. By the end of the day, she'd changed her mind, saying that he could stay long enough to finish school here, but that he should refrain from interacting with her in the mean time.

I've decided that I need to be more mobile. I need to be ready to leave with very little notice. I'll be sticking around until we move, I suppose, but then I need to get back on the job hunt, as well as hunt for apartments. Once I find something, I need to move out as quickly as possible, so having a bunch of stuff to move isn't ideal. I'm thinning down even more than before, and will group everything that I'm keeping into two categories. The first category is things that fit in a single box. I can put whatever I want in the box, as long as it fits. A lot of it will be frivolous, but I deserve to have at least *some* personal items. The second category is things that I can strongly justify keeping without being able to fit them in the box. There's no room for frivolousness in that category. I'll keep my files, many of which are needed for legal reasons. I'll keep my clothing for obvious reasons. Lastly, at least for now, I'll keep my laptop and server, also with a keyboard and monitor for when I need to work on the server directly. The rest of my computer parts that I have collected will either need to be fit into the box or let go of.

I had a couple choices in boxes. The first was bigger, but the dimensions didn't allow for my records to fit. I'm not quite ready to part with those unless I can sell them for at least ten dollars each, so I went with the smaller box. I've found that I have six audio CDs, six of which are freely-licensed and can actually be listened to. The nonfree one isn't my fault, it was given to me without my requesting it. I cannot justify keeping my broken ThinkPad X60s, but I'm also not ready to part with it, so that took up a chunk of my box space. I haven't located the cord to it yet though, so that might be either in one of the larger computer part storage bins that I need to go through, or it might just be lost. I've also gotten rid of three of the four buttons that I purchased from the FSF long ago. One just has a GNU head and mentions the domain name of the website. One says to fight for your right to play CDs, the issue being that some CDs are DRMed. I don't think that many companies produce DRMed CDs though, and I think that fighting CD DRM misses the point anyway. The thing with DRMed media is that it tends to be nonfree. Why should one fight to play nonfree media instead of buying free media instead? The last button mentions "SaaS" (instead of calling it "SaaSS"), but I don't know. I guess that that was never really my thing. The one that I'm keeping, if I even remember where it is correctly, is the rusty one that has the GNU, Linux, and FreeBSD logos on it and says to ask the wearer about free software. I'd love it if more people actually wanted to talk about free software and learn about why it's important. I've finally decided to get rid of those old FSF propaganda booklets. There's no room in my box of frivolousness for too much nostalgia, and I've already decided to keep several other things. I can't in any way justify keeping them outside of the box either, as they're released under a nonfree license. I cannot share them, I cannot show people what the FSF has to say. To subject people to such nonfree media would be unethical of me, and I can't really read them myself either. All that they are is baggage.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

He's been booted again.

Day 00425: Thursday, 2016 May 05

Our mother came into Cyrus' and my bedroom this morning yelling at Cyrus again. She can't stand the fact that Cyrus loves both of our parents instead of just her. I can't see this ending well for their relationship.

I've done a little work on the class that converts XHTML into plain text, but there's still a lot of progress to be made. I anticipate that converting <table/>s will be problematic. Dealing with the colspan and rowspan attributes of the table cells will be a pain. I've decided to remove <form/>s from the plain text output, as forms can't be submitted in plain text. Similar to the removal of <nav/> elements (which is now implemented), it'll clean up the output and make it more readable.

I spent most of the day working on laundry, washing dishes, and especially thinning down my belongings. I didn't really have time to look into my potentially-missing ThinkPad cord. I did get a little bit of research done though. I've located an official list (sort of a list, anyway) of XHTML5 elements. Down ear the bottom of that page, information on each element is linked to, so the link titles give me a fairly-definitive set of elements to work with. I plan to account for every valid element in some way, even if accounting for a given element is just making a conscious decision to ignore that element, as I'll do with the <span/> element. I've also located a strange URI scheme registration. Instead of registering a single scheme, it sort of registers the whole "web+" scheme prefix. I'm unsure of what this really means for me. No real scheme semantics are given and no schemes with this prefix are formally defined. The prefix doesn't show up on the official list of URI schemes because it's not a scheme, but the beginning of a scheme. Is there some list of scheme prefixes that I need to look up and account for? I couldn't find such a list, but that doesn't mean that it doesn't exist. After all, if there was no list, the registration of the "web+" prefix wouldn't be meaningful in any way.

When my mother arrived home today, she seemed much less angry than yesterday. She did rant about Cyrus and his "problems" while he wasn't there though. I carefully crafted a response to avoid any sort of blaming her, despite her being completely to blame. I said that one of the hardest parts of divorce for divorce children was that they had to choose a parent, making sure to say it as if needing to choose a parent was an inevitability, not something that one or more of the parents usually imposes on the children; something that she herself was imposing on her children. Thankfully, my careful phrasing paid off, and she seemed unphased by it. She did try to justify her unjustifiable actions though. She claims that by not choosing a parent, he's choosing our father over her, which of course is utter rubbish. There is no trying to argue with her though, and I know that. Once Cyrus got home, she actually asked him about his day, despite having said that she wants him to avoid her yesterday. She appeared to take an interest in his tests, as he had tests in every class today. (I'm assuming that these were final exams, but he didn't say.) I thought until that night that things were looking up.

My mother's school had some sort of literacy fair, so after she and Vanessa took the van to get there, I biked there myself. They had gratis books for anyone in third grade or below, but One of the kindergarten teachers offered Vanessa and I each a book. The small adult section had brand new books to choose from too! Being ostensibly nonfree, I won't be reading mine, but perhaps Vanessa will make use of it.

After Cyrus had gone to bed, our mother came in and started yelling at him some more. She was also pretty peeved that he wasn't very responsive, but that was because she'd woken him up and he hadn't had enough sleep. I'd be pretty unresponsive too! She told him to bring his suitcase to Springfield when he heads to our father's place for the weekend tomorrow, implying that he's once again officially booted.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I swear, I hate the WHATWG.

Day 00428: Sunday, 2016 May 08

While trying to research what to do about computing table cell widths for include.d's XHTML-to-plain-text conversion class, I ran across information hinting that the WHATWG has a presence on freenode. I've never been a fan of the WHATWG, as they tried to overthrow the W3C as the standards-setter for XHTML/HTML (and mostly succeeded in doing so). They revived HTML, which should be dead, and killed XHTML2, which should have been our new standard. HTML is messy and XHTML2 cleaned up most, if not all, of that mess. However, with the WHATWG being pretty much the people in charge now, and seeing as they are trying to get markup rendered similarly across all Web clients, I figured that I should pocket my disdain for the time being, pay them a visit, and ask for their advice. Avoiding their help doesn't undo the past and getting their help, provided I still follow the W3C's version of XHTML5 instead of the WHATWG's, doesn't further any bad parts of the WHATWG's agenda. Of course, freenode was being a pain as usual, so I wasn't able to connect right away. Trying to speed the process, I went to the WHATWG's website to see if this presence on freenode was official and if they also had a presence on other IRC networks. What I found there shocked me. In several places, it's mentioned that the WHATWG is opposed to the W3C's finalized version of the specification. They are against there being any stable standard, instead insisting that a "living standard" is the way to go. With a so-called "living standard", there is no way to be sure that a document is valid, as the definition of "valid" constantly changes. There's no way to measure compatibility. You can't say that Web client X is compatible with XHTML version Y, because there is no version Y, or any other version number. Worse still though is what this message tells us about the WHATWG. For example, take the following passage:

The W3C publishes some forked versions of these specifications. We have requested that they stop publishing these but they have refused. They copy most of our fixes into their forks, but their forks are usually weeks to months behind. They also make intentional changes, and sometimes even unintentional changes, to their versions. We highly recommend not paying any attention to the W3C forks of WHATWG standards.

We highly recommend not paying any attention to the W3C forks of WHATWG standards. They dismiss the W3C, recommending that people not pay attention to them. It doesn't matter to the WHATWG that they've effectively taken over XHTML/HTML, with the W3C mostly only giving stability to the WHATWG's standard. They want the W3C to keep their hands out of XHTML/HTML altogether!

The line above that passage is even more horrifying though. The WHATWG also works on other standards, such as the DOM, URL, and XMLHttpRequest standards. I don't know if the Document Object Model has any context outside the Web and XMLHttpRequest clearly has something to do with HTTP (in other words, the Web). The WHATWG is trying to redefine URLs though! What gall! URLs are the largest subgroup of URI. URIs span more than just use on the Web, and for them to be effective, they need a single, unified syntax, *not* one that's Web-specific. Furthermore, the WHATWG's strange URL specification is more difficult to understand than RFC 3986 and includes platform-specific nonsense such as Windows drive letters! URIs, including URLs, are not platform-specific and shouldn't include features that require parsing based on platform-specific operating system features. To be clear, their definition doesn't seem to require normalization in a platform-specific way, so URIs would still parse the same way on every platform, but all platforms would need to watch for syntax specific to other platforms when parsing, which is almost as bad. Perhaps I'd be less against the WHATWG redefining URIs if the WHATWG was a more competent group, but instead of sustainability, future compatibility, and document cleanliness, their main concern seems to be to codify what incorrect behavior Web clients currently exhibit and define a new "correct" based on that strange behavior. If the WHATWG was actually a competent group, their URL definition could be better than the IETF's definition simply because the IETF's definition is nonfree. However, the WHATWG was formed out of a perceived need to fight the cleaning of the HTML language, so it makes sense that they aren't defining reasonable standards.

In case anyone's curious, yes, the WHATWG's only official IRC presence did turn out to be on freenode.

I finished all the trivial work on my XHTML-to-plain-text class, but the thought of dealing with ordered lists and tables was too daunting for today. I even got <iframe/>s implemented, though not according to the specification. Unfortunately, the specification says that if the srcdoc attribute is specified, it represents a nested document with a text/html Content-Type. This is regardless of whether the containing document has an application/xhtml+xml Content-Type, clearly indicating that the author intended for the document to be XHTML, not HTML. I'm using an XML parser. I can't make it work on malformed markup such as unclean-yet-valid HTML code. My class isn't built to work on random pages found on the Web though, it's built to allow authors to mark up their documents in a real markup language, then present them as plain text files. If people plan to make use of such a markup class, they'll have to use that markup class' unique language. The fact that my class' language is identical to XHTML in all ways besides the handling of <iframe/> srcdoc attribute doesn't seem overly problematic. A real XHTML author would use XHTML in that attribute anyway, just making sure that their syntax conformed with the new HTML5 polyglot syntax, which conforms with both the XHTML5 rules and the HTML5 rules. That way, they'd have the well-formed-ness of XHTML but would still be following the specification by using HTML-compatible markup. After finishing with <iframe/>s, I should have completed the work on unordered lists, but it seemed a little too complex for today. I instead started looking for solutions to the more complex task of figuring out how to calculate optimal table column widths to minimize table height. When you're faced with a complex task, instead work on an even more complex task. Great idea, right⸮ Without any better idea than to calculate the table many times, once to try every possible column width, and choose the shortest table, I didn't have any idea how to complete the task at hand. Reluctantly, I decided to speak with people in #WHATWG, which is when I ran into the information that I found above. I'm still probably going to try to solicit their help though, as they might have information on how Web browsers typically deal with the problem of calculating optimal column widths, as they have to do something very similar to what I'm doing.

I continued thinning down my belongings today, though admittedly, spent most of my time instead trying to figure out what to do about <table/>s, so I didn't get a whole lot thinned down. I found my old FSF membership card, but I'm not sure what to do with it. I'm not sure if my membership has technically expired or not, but I certainly haven't considered myself a member for well over a year. The membership card doubles as a USB drive though, so if I erase Trisquel from it, it could be useful for small data storage.

Vanessa, our mother, and I went out to collect bullet shells for a while, and later, we went out to walk on the dunes. After we got home, Cyrus made it home as well.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Taking Cyrus' laptop

Day 00429: Monday, 2016 May 09

I found that for some reason, all my pages are using XML version 1.0. I don't really have any reason not to upgrade, so I upgraded. As it turns out, neither my Web browser nor the XHTML validator can actually handle XML version 1.1 for some reason. I had to revert back to XML version 1.0 to make everything work. I'm not yet sure if this is a bug in the Web browser and validator or if XHTML is limited to using XML 1.0. I'll have to look into that tomorrow.

At first, I couldn't bring myself to actually ask for help in #WHATWG, but after a bit, I sucked it up and asked if anyone had any ideas. TabAtkins said that table layouts aren't as standardized as they could be, but pointed me toward a draft specification. Assuming that I could make heads or tails of what it was saying, I think I found the section that would have helped me. But while I couldn't figure out what the draft meant, I did come up with an idea. After calculating each column's minimum length by finding the length of the longest word in each cell, I'll find the cell in each column that contains the longest string for that column. I can then use those string lengths to find a general ratio between column widths and apply it based on the width of the table. It's imperfect and will sometimes get the answer wrong, but it should work fairly well. Even that seems like a daunting task when performed iteratively though. Table cells can contain whole tables. I might end up instead using comma-separated value syntax instead, though I'll need to somehow escape commas and new line characters, especially when dealing with nested tables. A serialized, multidimensional array might also work, though I think that that would be too difficult to read and should be avoided. I've finished all non-table-related work on the class, at least for now, though it could use some fine-tuning later. For example, unordered list support currently has two problems. First, item numbers aren't treated as the text for list item bullet points. Instead, pound signs are used as the bullet points and the item numbers are treated as a textual part of the listed item. This is due to the fact that we don't know what the longest item number is until we completely finish processing the list. Unless we know what the longest number is, we don't know how far to indent the list to accommodate all of the numbered items. Second, reversed lists that don't specify a starting number begin at one, just like forward lists. Again, this is because we can't calculate the starting number until it's too late. Until we have a way to process the lists before processing the lists, I'm not sure how to fix these bugs. For the record, I would prefer to start lists at zero, but I'm trying to follow the standard as much as is feasible.

One of the grocery/department stores contacted me today to offer me a job. I had to decline, saying that I was only going to be in the area a couple more months. That was a bit sad, I think that it would have been a more long-term job than some others that I could have found.

When Cyrus got home, he informed me that before he left, our mother said that she was going to take his laptop when he left. That must be frustrating. He was worried about her taking it before, but he hadn't told me that our mother'd actually said anything about planning to take it. He wanted to back up his files, so I offered to lend him the SHYDRIVE, but he didn't take me up on that. I bet that most of his files would fit on that, especially if he deleted the music that he got from me. He could download the music from my computer once he had his new machine bought and set up.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

The causes of Vivian's migraines

Day 00430: Tuesday, 2016 May 10

Her whole life, Vivian has been getting migraines, but we think that they've gotten worse. She actually went to see a doctor, which she usually won't do. The doctor informed her that her skull plates fused together in an incorrect manner. As a result, they don't move in the correct direction, which may be causing the headaches. I'm a bit confused about this though, as I thought that once skull plates fused together, they no longer moved at all. If her skull plates fused together incorrectly, I'm not sure how they would go about trying to fix her skull. They're also considering the possibility of neurological damage though, which sounds pretty ominous. Lastly, they are trying to rule out dietary causes. Vivian's been asked to refrain from eating corn, gluten, milk, and soy. I know that if I accidentally ingest milk, I get bad headaches, though I don't think that I get migraines. If milk were indeed her cause, she'd be free of her migraines and would be one step closer to being vegan; she's already a vegetarian. I'm really hoping that milk is her migraine trigger, though honestly, no matter what the cause is, it would be awesome if they could find and fix it.

I didn't get hardly anything done on the coding front. I was just utterly lost as to how to render tables, especially nested tables, in plain text. I've come to a couple of conclusions though. First, perhaps table rows should activate some sort of single-line mode that prevents the converter from using new line characters. This would apply to nested tables too, so if one table is within another table's table cell, the inner table would be collapsed down to a single line. It's not pretty, but I can't come up with a single valid reason to nest tables. Nesting tables itself is not very pretty, and the only time that I've ever seen it done is to build website layouts, which is a misuse of the feature. I'm not dead set on this single-line mode though, so it's subject to change, at the very least, until I actually come up with an implementation. Second, and much more importantly, I came to my senses about trying to account for later data in current table cells while in the middle of converting a table. My converter is intended to be exceedingly simple. It's fine for it to monitor and record certain past events so that it can modify the rendering/interpretation of future elements. However, accounting for future elements in current rendering is out of the question. My converter should only look ahead as much as the current contents of the line buffer. Nothing later than the current line buffer, except perhaps the contents of the single-word buffer, should be used to alter the rendering of a given line. That is to say, my processing should be stateful, but it should wait for states to be set before actually being affected by them. I've been over-thinking this in an effort to make most well-formed pages render well in plain text format, but that goes beyond the scope of this project. Many poorly-written-yet-well-formed documents exist out there, and it's not my job to somehow make them look good. I only need a simple converter that does a simple-yet-effective job.

While I was outside weeding, one of the local cats was trying to get me to pay more attention to it. I talk to the cat, but I try to avoid touching it out of fear that it might have diseases. I'm not too worried about the effect of cat diseases on my own body, but I don't want to bring anything dangerous in to infect our own cat. The cat outside wasn't satisfied by my just talking to it though, and it kept stepping up on my leg and rubbing on me. Strangely though, it kept gently biting me! I've never had any cat gently bite me aside from our own cat, even past cats that we've had. I've only had them either refrain from biting or bite hard enough to inflict pain. Apparently, that behavior is not as uncommon as I thought.

I've been having a bit of a problem with the wrong Web browser being opened by a certain application, so I looked into Alternatives Configurator, a graphical application for configuring alternative applications for use (for example, to set a default Web browser). Strangely, this application demanded root's password. Normally, root doesn't have a password on a personal Debian system, and as a result, one can't log in as root. Instead, command line applications can be run with the sudo command and graphical applications will ask for the administrator's password, not the root password. Alternatives Configurator wouldn't accept an empty password or the administrator's password, and had to be started from the command line with sudo. The Alternatives Configurator option in the application menu is completely useless. It turned out that the alternatives system wasn't to blame though. None of the four Web browser options were set to the Web browser that this application keeps opening.

Document modifications

On 2018-01-16, my sister, Vivian, requested that I replace all instances of her legal name in my journal with the name "Vivian". She also asked that the name of the organisation she works for be redacted. This page was modified to fulfil that request.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I now fully embrace the use of the word "they" as a singular pronoun.

Day 00431: Wednesday, 2016 May 11

My transcripts from the high school came in the mail today. It seems that they didn't have a problem with the lack of a telephone number as I feared that they would. It's so hard to tell who is going to throw a tizzy over people's not having telephone numbers and who will just move on without a second thought. My grade point average on these transcripts isn't good. The problem was that I was depressed and didn't care about anything during that phase of my life. I barely even graduated. I later found out that my depression was caused by an unknown-to-me allergy to milk, so when I went vegan, that cleared up. It was too late to fix my grades though, I'd been out of school for quite a while. If the university actually gives me a chance, I'm certain that I can do better than back in high school, though they don't know that. I'm really hoping that they don't dismiss my application. Along with the transcripts came the immunization records that I requested. That means that they did have that information on file. I had only requested that record to see if they even had it, as they said that they don't have immunization records for every past student. I'll probably mail one of the official transcript copies tomorrow.

<table/>s are still being problematic, though I'm now contemplating simply using "[(nested table)[" and "]]" to denote one table that is interrupting another from the inside. This would allow me to keep tables fairly readable while still dealing with elements in the order in which they appear. The idea still needs some work though. I decided to take a ride through the local forested park to clear my head a bit. My goal was to reach all of the numeric landmark posts, most if not all of which mark forks in the path. I was going to try to visit them in order so that it'd be easy to know which ones I'd visited and not, but due to their layout, that would've required a lot of backtracking. Looking at their map, I found that all but one of the markers was on one of two main paths. Between the one marker that lies between the two paths and a downed bridge on one of the paths, some backtracking would still be required, but I could take a more efficient path by simply following the color-coded main paths. After a while, I passed a post that labeled the path that I was coming from as not being the one that I should have been on though. I wasn't sure if I'd taken the wrong path accidentally, if the map was wrong, or if the path marker was mis-labeled, but it was clear that my current strategy wasn't as effective as I needed it to be. I left the park and will try again tomorrow. Next time, I'll make a list of each trail marker that's supposed to be on each path in the order that I'm supposed to pass them. That way, I should know exactly if I make a mistake.

Having left the park far ahead of schedule, I rode down to the discount store to get an over-sized envelope to enclose the regular-sized envelope containing one of the official transcript copies so that it's ready to be sent tomorrow. I'm unsure of postage, but as usual, I'd prefer to take it into the post office myself as opposed to stamping it and leaving it in my mail box.

It bothered one of my friends that I used the word "it" to reference the cat that I interacted with yesterday while I was weeding the flowerbeds. They feel that use of the word "it" promotes the idea that cats are just object; cats deserve more respect than that. The fact is though, I've used the word "it" to describe baby humans as well. I use that word as the de facto pronoun for anyone that isn't likely to get offended by it. Sex and gender have nothing to do with most conversations, so there's no reason why either should be brought in through the use of segregated pronouns. The gender-based pronoun system is moronic and should be dropped. I've been using "he" and "she" when I think that I know the gender of someone that's likely to be offended by being called an "it" and "he/she" when I'm unsure. Using "he/she" is too clunky when the gender is known, but using "he" and "she" promotes this bifurcated pronoun system and helps it continue. I've avoided use of the singular "they" in any semi-formal context (such as my journal), as it's a plural word. Even in singular form, it takes plural verbs. You don't say "they is", you say "they are". To me, this meant that such singular use was invalid. I've avoided esoteric pronouns invented to solve this problem because they're not understood by most people and because most of those that do understand would probably think such avoiding of the usual pronouns is foolish; after all, most people don't seem to see any problem with the gender-based pronoun system. Change begins with yourself though. I need to drop masculine and feminine pronouns from my vocabulary. I did a Web serach and found that the most usable set of pronouns seems to be the Elverson pronouns, dating back as far as 1975. They are based on the word "they", and as such, would probably be mistaken as the singular "they" by most people. They're perfect for avoiding being part of the problem while also not standing out like a sore thumb in public. A bit later though, it was pointed out to me that the singular word "you" also takes plural verbs. Grammatically, "you" is a plural word, but it's perfectly accepted for use in referring to a single entity (for some reason, the dedicated singular pronoun "thou" has been mostly dropped from English). Singular "they" is no different, but is much more widely accepted than dedicated, singular, genderless pronouns. All that I really think that we need to do is de-gender singular pronouns, but if that requires removing the concept of singularity as well, it's worth the sacrifice. I now fully embrace the use of the word "they" as a singular pronoun.

While I was thinning down my belongings, I came across the old scrap laptop that I bought a while back for parts. Originally, the goal was to get my other laptop, thinkpad-x60s.local., to even boot. It turned out not to be needed though. Later, I did end up using the keyboard and one of the Wi-Fi cards, so the purchase wasn't a waste, but I still feel bad getting rid of the thing. Today, I took what will probably be the final part from it. I do need to thin down, and the off chance that maybe another part will be useful isn't enough to warrant keeping it around. thinkpad-x60s.local., in addition to killing every battery that it's used, has an overheating problem. I suspect that the fan has become damaged. I've removed the fan from the scrap laptop, and will likely attempt to swap the fans tomorrow. There are a few complications though. When I first tried to dismantle the laptop to look for bugs (as the NSA detained my laptop for a while during shipping), I couldn't get the thing apart. Some of the screws are stripped. Furthermore, removing the fan from the scrap laptop required ripping a strange, thin sponge that was glued across it. Hopefully that doesn't need to be intact, but I anticipate that removing the fan from thinkpad-x60s.local. will require similar damage. Lastly, the two laptops are slightly different models. I have no guarantee that the fan will even fit, and if it does fit, I'm not entirely sure that a messed-up fan is responsible for the overheating problem. All that I can do is try and hope for the best.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I may have managed to fix thinkpad-x60s.local..

Day 00432: Thursday, 2016 May 12

I managed to open up thinkpad-x60s.local. this time. I was either more determined than before or I had better tools. In any case, there was no sponge in need of ripping in this laptop, but several screws are stripped. The fan seems to be a drop-in replacement, I'm hopeful that this is all that's needed to fix the laptop. With how difficult it is to find screws on the inside when trying to dismantle the thing, I left most of the screws out. I doubt that this will be the last time that I need to perform repairs, so I want to make it easier next time. The components fit so snugly together that there's really not much chance that parts will be sliding around. I tried to use some of the screws from the scrap laptop to replace the stripped screws used on the outside of thinkpad-x60s.local., but the outer shells of the two are too different and the screws are different sizes. I can't really test thinkpad-x60s.local. right now, because though I did locate its power cord, I no longer have the instructions needed to boot the thing. Libreboot's default configuration doesn't account for encrypted hard drives and reconfiguring Libreboot requires writing to the motherboard's internal memory chip. If a mistake is made, the laptop will become unbootable and can only be fixed using special hardware that I don't have and don't know how to use. Step-by-step instructions were available, but I was always too afraid to try it. I may or may not try it at a later date, but for now, I'll just take the current operation's ostensible success as a victory and look for the booting instructions tomorrow. I might even still have the instruction file saved somewhere. It's probably on my mobile, as I wouldn't have been able to access the booting instructions when I needed them if they were on my hard drive.

I'm doing such a good job thinning down that I might be able to keep more than I thought. For example, I might be able to keep my random RAM sticks. All of the bigger items still need to go, but I thought that tinning down would be harder than it was.

I was running low on clean clothing, so I had to do a load of wash, despite the fact that the washing machine is still leaky. As I knew would happen, the laundry room floor was drenched and had to be mopped up. It was worth it though, wearing sweaty, dirty clothing sucks.

I dropped off the official transcript copy at the post office for delivery to the university. I should probably pay the university's application fee tomorrow.

I miss certain games from back when I lived in the proprietary software world, despite not having time for games anyway. As such, I've been hanging out in the #Tuxemon and ##Tuxemon channels on IRC. That game replicate and expands on a game that I used to really enjoy, but ostensibly without all the lock-in garbage and with full source code availability, reusability, and adaptability. It's still alpha-level software though as the developers put it, so it's not really playable yet. (I'd link directly to their website, but it maliciously discriminates against Tor users with a CloudFlare CAPTCHA wall. I'll trust that people that want to find the site will either grab the URI from the linked IRC channel's topic or perform a simple Web search.) One of the features that I saw mentioned on the main website (and before that, on the forum), is monster fusions. You can combine any two monsters in the game to make a new monster. These fused monsters aren't manually coded, but instead generated based on the ingredient monsters, allowing for unexpected surprises. In-channel, ShadowApe pinged me and said that they see me drop in from time to time, so I explained that I drop in whenever I can, but that it's difficult to connect to freenode and usually takes me several hours. A bit later, I noticed that they were the sole administrator currently in the channel, so I asked if they were one of the game's developers. They were! I made sure to thank them for their development time and effort, mentioning that I've missed this type of game since I gave up nonfree software. They said that they feel that this type of game is a perfect candidate for a free software project, as people could get creative and add their own new types of monsters to the game. I hadn't thought about it at the time, but people can also add their own new geographical locations, which is something that people often hack into proprietary types of such games, only for Turxemon, it'd actually be legal to do so. We discussed the monster-fusion mechanics a bit, and it turns out that it's less like fusion and more like breeding, only that all monsters are biologically compatible with all other monsters. When dealing with two purebred monsters, their offspring will be a halfbreed, taking on some traits from each of the two monster species. I'd read that fusing two fused monsters won't result in a combination of four creatures. Instead, only one gene from each parent monster is passed down, so there's still a finite number of available monsters, but most of them are things that the developers didn't explicitly think up. I asked about the results of fusing (breeding) two fused monsters that had the same types of parents. Is there a chance that you'll end up with purebred children? As it turns out, that's exactly how it works! It's a bit like oversimplified genetics. I can't wait for this game to actually be playable.

I ended up not going to the forested park today. I might not go tomorrow either. We have to get our yard sale set up, so I imagine that we'll all be working on that once everyone gets home.

My mother gets on Cyrus' case because he looks at images on some image-hosting site to relax. However, I found out today that she does the same thing, she just uses a different website. I really hate these double standards.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Chickens in the forest!?

Day 00433: Friday, 2016 May 13

I spent the morning in a state of laziness and lethargia. I didn't test thinkpad-x60s.local., I didn't work on include.d, and I didn't get anything else done. I think that I've managed to snap myself out of that funk though, so it shouldn't happen again, at least for a while.

I thought that we were going to work on setting up for a yard sale today, but that didn't happen. Instead, Vanessa, Cyrus, our mother, and I headed to the hills to look for bullet shells again. The hunt didn't seem to last long though, as we ran across a flock of four black and white checkered chickens that some farmer (or someone else) had abandoned in the forest. They couldn't have been there long. Otherwise, the coyotes would have caught and eaten them. We decided to try to rescue them and find a new home for them. Cyrus had brought tortillas, so Cyrus, Vanessa, and our mother crumbled them up and tried to lure the chickens over. Eventually, it mostly worked, and they became less afraid of us. It wasn't quite enough though, so when we tried to catch them, they all ran. After much chasing them in and out of the dense trees beside the road, I was able to catch two of them and our mother caught one, but we never did get the last one. That chicken will have to spend another night in the woods, trying to stay safe from predators. Much to my surprise, chickens aren't really all that good at defending themselves. They were afraid of us, but they didn't bite or scratch us at all. It could be that they weren't as afraid of us as they seemed, as they did calm down fairly quickly, but they did struggle to escape at first, just nonviolently.

I insisted that we show one of the chickens to our own house cat, Frances, just because chickens aren't something that she ever gets to see. I held the chicken and Cyrus held Frances. While holding the chicken this time, they grabbed onto my finger with their foot, letting me feel how warm these birds are! Come to think of it, I'm not sure that I've ever held a bird before today. I shouldn't have been as surprised by the warmth as I was though, as birds are warm-blooded creatures like we are. The chicken wasn't really interested in the cat, but Frances smelled the chicken for a while before completely losing interest. I set the chicken down so that they could see how the chicken moves, and that caught their attention again. Frances was kind of fearful of the chicken though, especially after the chicken had walked onto a bag of bullet shells, making a rustling sound. The chicken seemed entirely unafraid though.

Lastly, we put the chickens in the chicken coup out behind the house that we're renting. In all the months that we've been here, we've not had a use for that, but now it's come in handy. It'll provide more shelter for the chickens than they'd have had in the forest and the forecast calls for rain tomorrow. Their combined body heat within the walls should help as well. We gave them a water dish and more tortillas; they have the overgrown plants out there to eat. Are we going to try to sell the chickens in the yard sale tomorrow? I'm not sure. Cyrus also says that they have a friend that keeps some chickens and that perhaps this friend will want them.

Speaking of the rain tomorrow, if it does indeed rain, holding a sale won't really work. In addition to the rain potentially damaging the items to be sold, no one would really be out looking for sales in a downpour. From the sound of it, if it does rain, there's a high probability that we'll go out and try to rescue the last chicken instead of holding the sale.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Embedding parts of include.d

Day 00435: Sunday, 2016 May 15

I was thinking about gendered pronouns today, and came to the conclusion that they don't apply to non-human animals or to young children, even if you do use such pronouns. I forget at what age children begin to form a gender identity, but until that point, they don't have a gender yet. We also have no reason to think that non-human animals have a concept of gender. There is no reason to avoid using the pronoun "it" to describe them. I was shown an interesting Wikipedia article that makes me question whether gender is actually completely learned as I thought that it was. It may be mostly-genetic after all.

I wasn't of much help in setting up for the yard sale as I don't know what things are to be kept and which we are parting with. I did find a place to stash some of the things that we're keeping to get them out of the way though. I ended up putting them in my newly-empty closet. I also detangled a huge mess of cords. I wish that I could have done more. We ended up not holding the sale quite yet. We'll likely hold it next weekend.

Cyrus finally filed his taxes (late), but the tax preparation site didn't like his computer for some reason. Due to the fact that he swapped hard drives to preserve his data when our mother takes his laptop (as she's threatened to do that soon), he doesn't have Tor installed, so he was connecting from our home IP address. However, when I lent him my Tor-enabled laptop, the tax preparation website gave him less trouble. It still hassled him and kept locking up, but it actually allowed him to start and finish, unlike when he wasn't using Tor.

I branched include.d again, this time to work on a small side project. Preferably, when people use include.d, they'll put the whole thing on their include path and allow all other code to include it as needed. This setup works particularly well with a dependency-resolving package manager. However, there should also be an option to include parts of include.d in a project that uses them. This can already be done, but requires manually updating each function/class/constant file when there's an update to include.d. I'm building a function that will take a project and find all of the include.d files that are needed to make it function. I doubt whether it'll be perfect, and it'll probably make a few assumptions, such as that the include.d constructs in use are imported into a local name space, but it should make the process easier. The likely function output will be an array of files or an array of classes, constants, and functions that are used. In either case, it can be used to automate such an update.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I upgraded to Debian Testing without thinking about the consequences first.

Day 00436: Monday, 2016 May 16

I decided to upgrade my Debian system to the "Testing" branch today. The idea was that if I was on the Testing branch, I'd have newer versions of Web browsers, so I would know if the SNI bug fix had actually made it into any of the Web browsers in Debian. In the process of upgrading, I managed to bork Aptitude. With Aptitude out of commission, I was pretty worried. I still had a working copy of APT, but Aptitude is said to have better dependency handling and I don't like the idea of having it out of commission indefinitely. Once I finished the upgrade with APT, Aptitude returned to working order, so I guess that everything's fine now. Along the way, people in #Debian-Next recommended that I remove all software that wasn't from the Debian repository and remove those repositories from my source list, so I removed qTox and uTox. I don't really use those applications any more anyway and have sort of lost interest in them for now. Once they have their own URI scheme, I'll have a renewed interest, but for now, linking to my Tox "account" is more trouble than it's worth. I've also lost interest in TorChat and would uninstall that as well if it weren't for the fact that TorChat is the main way that two of my siblings usually contact me. During the upgrade, I lost my network connection due to the fact that Tor got uninstalled, and I was worried that I wouldn't be able to reinstall it. My source list contains nothing but onion-based repositories, so without Tor, I would be kind of stuck. Several things were to be uninstalled during the upgrade and I should have paid better attention to what would be lost instead of just spot checking to be sure that certain packages weren't on the list. Luckily, Tor wasn't to be removed, only upgraded, so the replacement had already been downloaded before the old version was uninstalled. After the upgrade was complete, I regained my network connection. Testing Web browsers didn't go as I'd hoped though. Arora isn't in Testing (though it's in both Stable and Unstable), so I couldn't check to see if the fix from Qt had worked. I'm guessing that Konqueror might use the Qt networking library as well, but if it does, the fix either doesn't work or hasn't made it to Debian and/or that Web browser yet.

Having finished the upgrade, I began work on include.d again. That's when I found my mistake. There was a reason that I hadn't upgraded my system to Testing yet. While having newer software on my client machine can help me test Web browser bugs, I need include.d to run on Debian Stable's version of PHP, so that's the version of PHP that I need to test on. The php command on the command now points to PHP7, and while that has many awesome new improvements, I should wait until those features are more widespread before using them. I do have the php5 command/binary at my disposal, but even that is too new to work for testing; it's at version 5.6.21. I backed my data up before I upgraded my system, but now I'm going to need to back up my data again and downgrade. I need my PHP 5.6.20 back. Then again, it's only one version behind. As a bug fix release, it might not be too problematic to use this newer PHP version.

Needing a break from the more tiresome parts of include.d development, I switched to the URI branch to begin work on the new scheme-specific classes. The first scheme on the alphabetically-arranged list was aaa:, but I found that that scheme, along with aaas:, doesn't conform to RFC 3986. I thought that I'd be able to put off the work on non-conformant schemes, but it looked like I wasn't going to be doing that after all. I needed an interface that the main URI class implemented, but that non-conformant URI classes also implemented. If a function or method wants a conformant URI, it can request that its argument(s) be of the main URI class, but if it only needs something that behaves mostly like a URI, it can request that its argument(s) only implement this interface, which has the method signature of every method from the main URI class. For implementing classes to truly behave like URI objects though, they need to implement every interface that the main URI class implements. I found that interfaces cannot implement other interfaces, but unlike non-interface classes, they can extend multiple classes. That feature is mentioned in the manual, but I didn't notice that and I had to discover it for myself. I find it strange that non-interface classes can only have up to one parent class while interfaces can have as many parent interface classes as necessary, but I suppose that it works. It would be nice to have multiple parent classes for certain non-interface classes though.

While I was debugging, jonez mentioned bbsengine on #PHP, so I asked about that. I asked about what bbsengine was, and they seemed a bit hurt that I didn't already know. As it turns out, it's a framework that jonez started building a few years ago. Trying to mend hurt feelings, I mentioned that I'm not the best developer; I don't know many frameworks and I either use code as-is, not knowing what frameworks it makes use of, or write the functionality that I need into my own framework. Jonez said that they'd be honored if I reviewed bbsengine, so again, trying to avoid hurting people, I agreed to do it. I just bought myself some extra work. Perhaps I'll learn something from it though. At least it's written in PHP, so I stand a chance of understanding it, and it's covered by the GNU LGPL, so I don't have to waste time looking at proprietary code. (I did check the license before agreeing to review the code.) I'm confused as to why it would be an honor for *me* to review the code, but I might look into that tomorrow after downgrading my Debian installation, assuming that I even decide to do that.

I noticed that the Tox team is dealing with trademark issues. It seems that someone claiming to be related to the Tox group by calling themselves "Project Tox". I'm not sure what's going on, but it sounds like the real Tox developers think that the impostors may be NSA officers that are building botnet software into their modified Tox software. I sincerely hope that there's actual evidence that "Project Tox" is doing this. Either missing source code or source code containing such antifeatures would be perfect evidence, for example.

Speaking of trademarks, it seems that Debian Testing has Firefox. Not Iceweasel, but Firefox. Mozilla has publicly acknowledged that Debian's security patches, system-related functionality patches, and packaging are not in violation of Mozilla's trademark policy. They have requested that Debian use the Firefox branding once more. Mozilla's also decided to offer better support for stability, providing an extended support release, which only provides security patches for a while; it doesn't include new and potentially-unstable features. This is more in line with what Iceweasel has/had, but these Firefox releases don't have support for as long as Iceweasel's do. For some reason, the Debian team is meeting them halfway though. The Debian team has agreed to use Firefox's new extended release version whenever the last one expires. This seems like a downgrade as far as Debian's stability is concerned. That said, I don't use Debian for the stability, I use it for the freedom. Debian is one of only two operating systems that I know of that are committed to using only free components. The FSF keeps a list of distributions that they like, but as far as I know, these distributions make no such commitment in regards to non-software components, such as graphics and manuals. The FSF's guidelines allow these things to be nonfree, but personally, I don't find this to be acceptable. Back on the topic of trademarks, it was pointed out that Mozilla trademark policy prohibits sale of binaries, but it seems to be believed that Debian falls into a loophole because they build their own binaries. I think that this loophole is simply a miswording on Mozilla's part, and that while this interpretation does follow the word of the policy, it doesn't follow the spirit of it. In any case though, it seems that it is believed that Mozilla's trademark policy is now close enough to that of other projects that it's palatable to the Debian team, so Iceweasel will soon be no more. Annoyingly, the switch to Firefox reset my default search engine to be Google, though the rest of my settings seem to have been preserved.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Rushed voting and even dollar amounts

Day 00437: Tuesday, 2016 May 17

I briefly looked over bbsengine as I said I'd do yesterday. The first thing that I noticed was that there's a JavaScript directory. Bbsengine is partly written in JavaScript! Bbsengine is probably specifically for Web development. Hopefully it has fallback options for clients without JavaScript support. It also incorporates other frameworks, delegating responsibility to them and allowing them to do what they do best. That's probably a good idea. Lastly, I checked what I'd actually set out to check first before noticing other features. Bbsengine's own code, the code not inherited from other frameworks, is not namespaced. That makes it easier for bbsengine to conflict with other frameworks and libraries. I recommended the \org\bbsengine namespace to jonez, and jonez agreed that the code should be namespaced. However, they first built it in the pre-PHP5 era. (Namespaces were added in PHP 5.3, which is why I won't touch a PHP interpreter that's older than that.) Because bbsengine spans both PHP and JavaScript, it's outside the scope of what I do, so I can't properly evaluate it. It serves a use case that I don't understand.

Back to working on my own library, include.d, I briefly considered the possibility of renaming the \st\y\uri\known_scheme abstract class and using the \st\y\uri\known_scheme name for an interface. This would allow functions and methods to request that their arguments be objects of a class that implements URIs of a known scheme without requiring that that scheme's syntax actually conform to valid URI syntax. I quickly dismissed the idea though. There's no particular reason why a function or method would need to know that the URI-like object has a known scheme and URI-like strings that don't conform to URI syntax shouldn't be grouped with actual URIs any more than they already are with the URI interface. I started work on implementing the aaas:- and aaa:-schemed "URI" classes, but quickly backtracked. I'll probably undo most of what I did today when I next work on include.d. I've also set up a page to keep track of all the URI schemes that make use of illegal scheme-specific syntax, which I will add to as I progress.

I paid a visit to the local forested park again. First, I rode to the other side of it, where the map is, so that I could plot my route through it to reach all of the landmark posts. I found a fairly efficient route with minimal backtracking, and memorized a few patterns that the numbers on the posts made so that I could make sure to hit each one. On one side of the park, the posts were in mostly-numeric order, but on the other side, one path used even numbers while the other side used odd ones. I couldn't help but notice that three post numbers were skipped though, left entirely off the map and probably left out of the park: posts zero, thirty-one, and thirty-three. If I'd tried to visit the posts on order as I'd originally planned to do days ago, the missing post zero wouldn't have thrown me, but the missing posts thirty-one and thirty-three would have confused me to no end. I'm glad I instead decided to plot a route that ignored the order of the posts.

I forgot to mention on Sunday that my mother found a random person online that wanted the chickens that we'd found. My mother says that from the looks of how they and their child handled the chickens, they looked like they knew what they were doing and were who they claimed to be. They claimed to already have several chickens. My mother was worried that they might want to use them as targets or something, but seeing as they knew what they were doing, my mother was no longer worried. My mother recognizes knowledgeable chicken-handling because they grew up on a farm herself.

I've been busy lately and totally forgot about the upcoming election. It doesn't help that I've been a bit out of the political loop either, seeing as political groups are jam-packing my inbox to the point where I couldn't process it all. Luckily, a friend reminded me that ballots were due in today. I didn't have time to research every candidate, so I didn't vote for every office as I'd originally intended to. Instead, I voted for Sanders and against Clinton, then did some quick research on the other two country-level offices. (I believe that these offices were for Senator and House Representative, but I was in a rush, so I didn't really take note.) I chose the first candidates that I found on the list of options that seemed to support net neutrality from what I could see online about them. For all other offices, if there was one person running (as was the case for many offices), I voted for them, and otherwise, I didn't vote for that office. I would have loved to vote for the state, precinct, and county offices, but an unresearched vote is worse than no vote, and I simply didn't have time. It seems that all the republican presidential candidates dropped out aside from Trump, so as the presidential election was the only one that my mother cared enough to bother with and they're registered as a republican, they decided not to vote.

Cyrus, Vanessa, our mother, and I all went out to the hills again to look for bullet shells. Along the way, our mother was talking about all the ways that their students were annoying them as usual, and part of it had to do with a pseudo-money math exercise. I asked if all the prices were in even dollar amounts, to which they replied that no, some of the pretend items cost only one dollar. I tried to explain that one dollar is an even dollar amount, but they insisted that it wasn't; it was an odd dollar amount. I tried to explain that even dollar amounts have nothing to do with even and odd numbers, and that it just means whole dollar amounts, but as usual, they insisted otherwise. I swear, my mother sucks at understanding basic concepts, especially when mathematics or technology are even tangentially involved. One time, they even argued to the figurative death that if you flip a coin twice, there's a one hundred percent chance that you'll get a heads, but also that a one hundred percent chance doesn't mean that an event is guaranteed to occur. I never could get through to them about percentages, and I didn't even bother to try today with the concept of even dollar amounts. It's simply not worth the argument.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

We need to get out when we can.

Day 00439: Thursday, 2016 May 19

I spent much of the day weeding the flowerbeds again. This time, I found some of those thick-leafed, cerated desert plants that hoard water in their leaves like a cactus does in its thick stem. What are desert plants doing in a coastal flowerbed? They say that you're not supposed to water such plants often as they'll easily drown, but they survived our constant rainfall. Then again, I think I've seen an occasional cactus patch planted in Springfield as well, so maybe they are more resistant to water than people say. When my mother got home though, they told me off about the weeding, saying that I should know better than to think that that was a good use of time. They're the one that said that we should probably weed in the first place though! She said that I should instead wash the dishes, finish sorting my belongings, and work on sorting family belongings based on if we are keeping them or not. I cleaned the dishes as asked, though that's normally Cyrus' job. There's no reason why I'd think to do that instead of weeding. Admittedly, I should have finished sorting my belongings by now. It's so difficult to give up almost all of your belongings though, so I've put finishing off longer than I should have. As for sorting the family stuff, I can't really do that. If I was the one actually deciding what needed to stay and go, it would be different, but as-is, I can only make guesses. A bit later, my mother started going off about how they were evicting Cyrus, then the two of them went down to the bank to clean out Cyrus' bank account, leaving Cyrus with nothing. Our mother didn't actually evict Cyrus as they said that they would though, so that was a relief. They're staying around for now. This really doesn't feel like a stable home for any of us. After we move, I need to find a job, save up, and get myself out of here. If Cyrus wants, they can come too, and Vanessa can join us when they come of age and can legally choose to move out.

I told my mother about my "one box" plan the other day, my plan to keep only one box of items that aren't strictly necessary. The first thing that they asked was if my computer would fit. They were implying that computers aren't a necessity in this day and age! I can't even apply for certain jobs without a computer and I certainly can't check my email for responses to job applications and resumes without one. In any case, I'm now going to try to pack my laptop in my one box, further limiting my space. I can't pack the server in the box though, as it won't even fit in the box even if it's the only item there. I argue that I need it to keep my sanity and for data backups, so hopefully my mother won't try to get me to get rid of that as well. I'm already trying to keep the number of frivolous belongings that I have to a minimum, I deserve to have at least something that I can keep.

Another of my teeth started falling apart now. One of my back teeth now has a jagged break and is cutting into the inside of my cheek a bit. I inherited bad teeth from my mother, there's not much that can be done about this. I have a lifetime of bad tooth heath to look forward to. I'll have the dentist take a look at this tooth too when I get in for my appointment.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

My mother doesn't understand compromise.

Day 00440: Friday, 2016 May 20

I received a letter by post today informing me that the signature on my primary election ballot has been challenged. My legal name is now going on record on the list of voters whose signatures have been challenged and unless I mail in a new voter registration via post and it arrives before the thirty-first of the month, my vote won't count and I'll lose my right to vote and sign petitions until I've sent it in. For some reason, the voter registration form requires first class postage, but at least that means that it'll probably arrive on time, as letters mailed first class are supposed to arrive in one to three days.

While I was out delivering the form to the post office, I took the opportunity to check on my dental appointment time. I knew that it was on the twenty-third, but I failed to keep track of what time it was. I believed that it was at 13:00, but I wasn't entirely sure. As it turns out, it was actually at 15:00, so it was a good thing that I double checked.

My mother was complaining that the fruit and vegetables are going bad before anyone eats them. I used to use them for making soup, but when my mother started complaining about the smell of my cooking, I had to switch to mostly just eating prepackaged foods. Cyrus asked if maybe I could use the remaining onions before they went bad, so I had to remind them of why I don't cook. Our mother had the gall to claim that I didn't stop cooking for her! I've been feeling awful since I quit cooking. I think I'm a bit malnourished. I'm certainly not doing this for myself! My mother claims that if I was really doing it for them, I'd quit being vegan, as that's what they really want. Clearly, my mother doesn't understand compromise at all. They've asked me to do two things: to quit cooking and to quit being vegan. I've done the only one of the two that I can do with a clear conscience. I'm doing as much for them as I ethically can.

My mobile is on the fritz again. This time, it refuses to read SD cards that are formatted as Ext4, claiming that they are all damaged. It can still read FAT SD cards, but that doesn't really help me. I need the SD cards to store my music collection; each track's file name is based on the name of the song, the album name, and the name of the album artist. Several artists titled their songs as questions, which is perfectly reasonable, but FAT can't handle question marks in file names. It doesn't seem worth it to copy my music collection and check through the copy looking for titles that aren't FAT-compatible. FAT simply doesn't have any redeeming qualities as far as I'm aware and there's no point wasting time trying to force FAT to work for me. This is frustrating, hopefully I can get my mobile straightened out.

It's been bothering me that a PHP interface can't ensure that methods do what they are meant to do. Instead, they can only require that the methods be present and accept the desired arguments. I need to be able to insure that some classes behave very much like the main URI class, but these classes cannot extend the main URI class. The main URI class parses, validates, and normalizes the basic URI syntax. However, some URI schemes use a nonconformant scheme-specific syntax. I considered changing my new interface into an abstract class, but even that presents problems. It could insure that the basics are implemented properly, though it would need to be less strict than the main URI class. It wouldn't be able to parse URIs, that would be left to child classes to implement. Instead, it would only handle basic data getting/setting and serialization/deserialization. The serialization method would just redirect input to the __tostring() method and the deserialization method would just redirect input to the __construct() method, a method that must be defined in child classes. However, this setup would open up the main URI class (which would extend this class) to nonconformant data by allowing child classes of the main URI class to call methods from the abstract class directly, bypassing the validation and normalization provided by the main URI class. The abstract class' setters could be called with malformed strings. This isn't acceptable. If a class wants to be treated as a URI without being subjected to this normalization and validation, it should extend the abstract class and not the main URI class. If an object is detected to be of a class that descends from the main URI class, it should be possible to expect that class to conform to the basic standards.

As a side note, I've been using a sort of pseudo-namespace within the \st\y\uri namespace for URI-related classes that don't directly implement a specific URI scheme. Basically, I've been using well-placed underscores to insure that these classes aren't interpreted as scheme names by a planned method that will try to detect the correct class to use based on the scheme of a URI. Underscores will be used by that method to encode characters that may appear in URI schemes but that may not appear in PHP labels. This means that only three characters will ever appear after an underscore in one of my scheme-implementing classes: ef (representing a full stop), aitch (representing a hyphen), and pee (representing a plus sign). If I make sure to use an underscore in all of the intermediate classes and follow that underscore with any alphanumeric character that isn't on that list, those classes won't confuse the method that uses the scheme-related classes, so that's what I've been doing. This is the wrong way to go about this. Some of these classes aren't ones that I'd normally even want an underscore in the name of, as they seem like single-word class names to me. As I said, this creates a sort of pseudo-namespace. Why should I be using fake namespaces? That seems awfully messy when I have real name spaces at my disposal! Next time that I have time to work on include.d, I should move all of these classes into their own sub-namespace.

At the end of the day, we put together our garage sale signs so that we can get them set up tomorrow. Also tomorrow, it seems that we'll have overnight guests. My mother has friends that are in town for some sort of religious event and want a place to stay so that they won't have to drive home tired.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Not selling records and CDs after all

Day 00441: Saturday, 2016 May 21

While we were setting up for the yard sale, my mother jokingly asked if I wanted a broken-off piece of a curtain rod that was kind of ornate. In response, I jokingly said that it wouldn't fit in my box, so they said that they were good at packing and could make it fit. I explained that I was already having enough trouble making things fit and that I have an extra box of things that I haven't made fit or gotten rid of yet. I still need to consolidate these two boxes into one, so adding more stuff wasn't a likely possibility. They said that it must be nice being able to fit all my stuff into a single box, but that struck me as kind of odd. Yes, all my stuff will fit in this one box by the time I'm done, but it's because I'm getting rid of most of the things that I care about, which is something that they could do as well. Carefully wording my reply, I explained that it was because I was getting rid of items that I actually wanted to keep, making sure not to say anything that could be interpreted as a statement that they should do the same. I don't care if they thin down as much as I, but a misinterpreted statement might set them off again. Before moving to Coos Bay though, I had already gotten rid of everything that I wanted gone. The only things left are those that I still want to keep. They replied that I didn't need to get rid of that much, that because they were thinning down too, I wouldn't need to thin down as much. Thankfully, they haven't picked up on my real motivation. They always accuse me of being a burden because I don't drive a motorized vehicle. They say that part of the countless trips between houses are my fault, as my stuff is amongst what was/is being brought. If I can fit all of my stuff crowded in the front seat with me, that's space that isn't being taken up by my stuff; less that they can try to accuse me of. The single box is an arbitrary line that I drew, as without some sort of line, there would be no measurable goal. I can't just take what I think will fit in the front seat with me, as I still need to account for my necessities, which will likewise be up there with me. However, though they previously questioned my need for a computer, they are now saying that I don't need to thin down so much. I think that I might stash //newdawn.local. in its laptop case, leave //thinkpad-x60s.local. in the box as originally planned, and stash cords in the laptop case with //newdawn.local.. With the cords and //newdawn.local. no longer taking up space in my box, I think that I can fit the rest in. It's worth noting though, in case I haven't already said this, that the one-box plan won't be concluded after we move. It's a new life style in which I can be ready to pick up and go with little notice.

Unfortunately, my mother didn't want me to try to sell my CDs if I wasn't going to severely mark them down, so sadly, I didn't even get to try selling them. I thought it best not to mention the records and I had had the same plan with them, so I left those inside and out of the sale as well. If I'd have been able to sell my two full-size records, it would have also helped with my box situation. Those two records are too tall and require a taller box. If I was able to use a shorter-but-wider (not wide enough for the records though) box, I'd actually have more space.

Most of the day was spent setting up the sale and watching the sale, but we didn't get many customers.

I was able to get my mobile to read some Ext4 SD cards, just not the one that I need it to. These cards are all too small. If the mobile *is* reading these Ext4 cards though, maybe the problem isn't the mobile after all. Maybe the card is damaged in some small way that the mobile can't tolerate but that a laptop can tolerate without error. At the same time though, the mobile can read the card that I want read if I format it as FAT, which hints that the SD card isn't the one that's broken. I'm not sure what to do.

I needed to work with KeePassX today, which apparently is the first time that I've used it since upgrading to Debian Testing. I'm not happy with it. First of all, it uses a new database format and refuses to write using the old format. It'll read the old format, it just can't export or save to that format. This means that I can no longer share a password file between my mobile and my Debian system as KeePassDroid uses the old format. I would write this off as KeePassDroid being the problem as it's using an outdated format, but KeePassX is presenting other problems as well that are clearly downgrades from past performance. For example, the old KeePassX defaulted to using twenty-five character passwords, but the new one defaults to using sixteen-character passwords. This can be changed, but it's still a worse default. More importantly, KeePassX no longer allows you to use spaces during password generation and doesn't offer the option to specify a custom character set. Some pesky websites demand non-alphanumeric characters in passwords but disallow several of the normal candidates. Short of regenerating the password a few dozen times, the only option was to specify a custom character set that included all alphanumeric characters plus the non-alphanumeric characters that the website allows/requires. This is no longer an option though.

Two of my mother's friends came over to spend the night, though the four of us went out to dinner first. They seem like nice people, though the younger of the two seems to be obsessed with a particular proprietary game series.

I decided to relax my requirements for my abstract URI base class. Simply put, I need serialization and deserialization to function as string typecasting and instantiation, respectively. This is non-negotiable. String getting and setting only needed to be implemented in the abstract class to allow the string typecasting method to be implemented in the abstract class; it allowed the string typecasting method to know where the needed data was stored. Child classes can do all sorts of strange things though. They don't have to store the data where they should and there's no reason to try to make them. It would be nice to have the __tostring() method always output something semi-reasonable, but by removing that requirement, I can get everything else that I want out of the abstract class.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Dental appointment

Day 00443: Monday, 2016 May 23

My dental office visit today began with filling out several sheets of paperwork. most of it seemed reasonable, but a few of the questions were strange. Two in particular stood out to me. One asked if I felt safe at home. Honestly, I don't really. The head of the household is unstable and I'm almost certain that they're bipolar. They've threatened to boot Cyrus, Vanessa, and me several times, and they *did* boot Vivian at least twice. Likewise, I can't even take care of my own nutritional health here. It's not the safest place to be, but it's the best that I have for now. I considered leaving this question blank as I didn't want to answer it, but fearing that that would set off some red flags that might lead to something, I lied and said "yes". The second oddball question asked how much I fear dental work. In truth, dental work mortifies me! I wasn't going to put that on the form though. I keep my fear on the inside very well, and it isn't going to interfere with any procedures that they perform. With no obvious downside to leaving that one blank, I did.

The main thing that they did today was just take radiographs of my teeth. I forgot how much those hurt! The radiation itself doesn't hurt of course, and the subtle feeling that I got from it was likely psychosomatic, but they have one bite down on this small piece that digs into the roof and floor of one's mouth. I didn't count them, but it felt like they took about thirty radiographs by the time that they were done. For a few of them, they pointed the x-ray machine directly at my eye, which was kind of scary! I don't think that they'd do that if it was likely to cause a problem, but I've had severe eye issues in the past, so the thought that something might damage my eyes further wasn't a pleasant one. After taking a look at my teeth, the dentist said that five of my teeth couldn't be saved and would have to be removed. I asked about implants to replace them, but it seems that my insurance will only cover implants if I am missing six non-wisdom teeth and three of my bad teeth are wisdom teeth. I probably don't need my wisdom teeth, I suppose, but having a missing other tooth on each side of my mouth is going to be inconvenient. The dentist wanted me to get another radiograph taken, but the necessary equipment in their office. Instead, they wanted me to go all the way to Bandon tomorrow to another of their offices! I'm not sure what kind of radiograph that they're after, but I explained that I use my bicycle for transportation and that that was quite a distance to bike! They said that insurance would actually cover a taxi ride though, and arranged for a taxi to pick me up tomorrow. I guess I'm going to Bandon tomorrow. Lastly, it seems that they didn't actually need to see my photo ID or my insurance card, despite having told me I'd need both in their last letter to me. It's better to have them and not need them than to need them and not have them though.

Later in the day, one of my two main bad teeth broke further. It's frustrating, but I suppose that it doesn't matter too much. After all, that whole tooth is going to be removed.

For some reason, my IRC client has been connecting and disconnecting to and from the Volatile IRC network every ten minutes, which has been annoying wowaname. The ten-minute interval implies that Tor is involved somehow. Tor changes circuits every ten minutes, so it'd be an amazing coincidence if the similar intervals were not related. I don't know whether the issue is caused by my Tor instance or the instance running the Volatile onion address, but because of the issue, wowaname banned me from #Volatile! This is highly insulting. People in #Volatile, including wowaname themselves, constantly flood the channel with Unicode art. When they do this, it disrupts conversation and makes it impossible to read what other people are typing. Wowaname has no problem with this and in my opinion seems to encourage it. I never disrupt conversation like this. However, wowaname considers one join and one part that I can't control only every ten minutes, that's two lines added to the channel each time, to somehow be the bigger problem. Clearly wowaname has their channel-moderating priorities backwards.

My mother insisted that I ask the dentist tomorrow when I go in for the next radiograph if I'll be put under. They claim that they need to know if they'll need to pick me up once I get out. I refused the ride, but they wouldn't take "no" for an answer. I'll ask tomorrow I suppose in order to avoid conflict, but the ride isn't happening. If they were going to put me out, they should have mentioned that already, especially if it was going to leave me incapacitated after the operation, so I doubt that anything like that will happen. If they are going to put me out though, I'll verify that I'll still be fine to either walk or bike home. If I won't even be able to make the trip on foot safely, I'll cancel the procedure rather than get the ride. Because the teeth are to be pulled, it's not like there's still a chance to save them if they are taken care of soon enough. There's no urgency. It's bad enough that I'm taking a taxi to Bandon, I'm not also getting a ride to somewhere so close.

Document modifications

On 2018-01-16, my sister, Vivian, requested that I replace all instances of her legal name in my journal with the name "Vivian". She also asked that the name of the organisation she works for be redacted. This page was modified to fulfil that request.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Taxis and a radiograph

Day 00444: Tuesday, 2016 May 24

The taxi driver showed up in my driveway, though they didn't alert me to the fact that they'd arrived. They didn't show up at the beginning of the expected arrival time window and I wasn't going to stare out the window until they arrived. They didn't show up late or anything, but it would have been nice to let me know so that they could get moving and not waste as much of their own time. The whole trip there, the driver was pretty quiet. Once we arrived, the driver left. Yesterday, the driver had been told to wait for me because my appointment was going to be super short as they only needed to take a single radiograph, but I guess that the driver didn't care. Maybe it was due in part to the fact that we arrived a bit early. Due to my mobile being on the fritz, I didn't have it on me, so I don't know how early we'd arrived, but due to arriving during their lunch period, I needed to wait outside until their doors were reopened.

Once in, the visit was just as quick as they said it would be. The dental assistant at this place mentioned something about a "pano", but when I asked what was said, they just said that it was the radiograph that I was there for. I specifically asked if I had heard correctly and if "pano" stood for "panoramic", and that was indeed the case. Why couldn't the dentist from yesterday just tell me that they wanted a panoramic radiograph? Then I'd have a better idea of why I needed to visit this more distant office. This x-ray machine was much nicer than the one that the first dentist used as well. In addition to being able to capture an image of all of my teeth in a single image as was the purpose of coming in, it also didn't hurt like the small thing that the other dentist needed me to bite down on. I'm almost certain that anything that would be needed on the small radiographs could easily be gotten from this panoramic one, so it's kind of annoying that they used the painful small one at all. They probably only use the small one instead in some offices for budget reasons.

With the appointment over, I explained my situation to the receptionist and asked what to do about the taxi that left without me. The receptionist contacted the taxi dispatch people, but it took an hour for them to arrive, according to the taxi driver that showed up. I really should have brought my laptop, but I had no idea that this was going to happen; it wasn't supposed to, as the first taxi driver was told to wait. The driver that came to pick me up this time was a different taxi driver than last time though, and this one was much more friendly and talkative! It turns out that this driver likes to make gay jokes but is also openly gay themselves. Before taking me home, they picked up and dropped of another person in town, then on the way home, they explained how the taxi system works a bit. It seems that the insurance people refuse to pay the full fair for a second passenger if the first passenger is in the car still. If there is a group of several people needing an insurance-covered lift, taxi drivers are required to choose between providing decent customer service by taking them all at once or making money by taking each person one at a time. Employees should never have to choose between making money and providing decent service; they're either rewarded for poor service or punished for good service. This driver had another option though, they instead doctor the books. They claimed not to have picked me up until dropping the other person off, that way they would get their proper payment while still providing the expected level of service. Additionally, the shared ride cuts down on fossil fuel usage, so I was plenty happy to just go along with that. The final thing that we discussed was the needs of the taxi drivers and the needs of the taxi company. On one side, the taxi drivers need there to be few drivers, as it means that there are more customers per taxi, allowing the drivers to make a living. On the other side, the taxi drivers have to pay a fee to the taxi company just to be allowed to drive the taxis, so the company needs more drivers to cover their costs. There's currently someone caught in the middle, trying to balance the two needs in this company, but neither side seems to understand the other, so this person is taking heat from both sides. This driver does seem to understand, but the way that they explained it, this wasn't the norm. I'd hate to have to be in opposition to my bosses. Even if I wasn't against driving, I don't think that I'd want to be a taxi driver.

Once I was back in town, I went back to the first dental office, where they set me up with an appointment to have teeth from one side of my mouth removed on September first at nine. Their plan was to remove teeth from the other side in a later appointment. I'm not even sure if I'll be in town still though for the first appointment, so I will likely have to cancel it. It seems that they allow pentalty-free appointment cancellations up to but not including the final twenty-four hours before the appointment, so I'll keep the appointment until I know for sure what's going to happen.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Rediscovering SuperTux

Day 00449: Sunday, 2016 May 29

The landlords never did come into the house to look at the light fixture. Instead, they exclusively continued work in the yard.

Mostly, I took the day off. I decided to play SuperTux for a bit, but that had gotten uninstalled when I upgraded my Debian installation to Testing. Upon reinstalling it, I found that the old version of SuperTux wasn't present; instead, it was "SuperTux 2"! Previously, SuperTux 2 was just the unstable version of SuperTux. The "2" was just present in package names to allow the unstable version to be available in package managers that wanted it while still allowing the stable version to be available alongside it. I thought that it'd never stabilize because any stable version would just be released as "SuperTux". While I wasn't paying attention, the SuperTux team released a new stable version: version 0.4.0. My best guess is that because it's so different from their last stable version, version 0.1.3, they decided to use the ~/.supertux2 configuration directory and avoid any buggy behavior cased by old configurations/saves; to just start fresh. The application menu item may have been left with the name "SuperTux 2" and the window title bar left with the name "supertux2 v0.4.0" just for consistency. It also seems that SuperTux now has an Esperanto language pack! The system language (Esperanto) was detected by SuperTux automatically, but the language pack in use is also configurable. This game even has USB game pad support, though it doesn't seem to work by default. In order to get controller support to work, you need to enable the "Manual configuration" option, at which point the default controller configuration becomes active until you change it. Some of the defaults worked with my game controller (which is how I was able to tell that the controller wasn't working at all without the manual configuration option active, but some configuration was necessary in order to make certain actions (such as jumping) possible. Perhaps some controllers work entirely with the defaults, but it might still be nice to choose your own preferred button layout. Once properly configured, game controller support works perfectly! In addition to the game controller being better for gaming than a keyboard, my keyboard doesn't respond well to having more than two or three keys pressed at a time, so using the controller instead is an easy way to bypass that issue. I have to say that SuperTux is much more polished now than it used to be. It plays like a professionally-made game now! There's even new challenges such as the task of collecting every coin in a given level and eliminating every enemy in a given level, either of which can be complicated by paths that can only be traveled once, such as those built from falling platforms. Though I do plan to revert my system to Debian Stable when I have time, I'll pull this new SuperTux version from the backports repository. I love this new SuperTux and don't want to go back to the old version!

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Laundry day

Day 00450: Monday, 2016 May 30

I finally paid my application fee to University of [REDACTED]. I meant to pay it the same day that I received the email from them, but I ended up getting busy and distracted.

The original plan for laundry day was for my mother to drop me off at the laundromat with the clothing while they went out collecting bullet shells or something. I'd do the laundry while they did something else. However, there was a change of plans. My mother is aware that the landlords aren't happy with the lack of yard work we've been doing. I would have had the flowerbeds cleaned up, but my mother told me to stop working on that, viewing it as trivial. As for the rest of the yard work, we really aren't the landscaping and gardening type like the landlords seem to be. Likewise, we're paying a very large monthly sum to them ($1300 USD). At that price, it really isn't our job to manage their property. With them being unhappy and having a key to the house though, my mother didn't feel safe leaving Vanessa and Cyrus alone with them. Instead, they left me at home with Cyrus and took Vanessa with them to do the laundry. Once they finished the wash, they brought the damp clothing home, where I dried and folded it. I didn't finish the job though, as my mother was exhausted and fell asleep in the living room. I put that task aside as to not wake them up, then when they woke up, they wanted to head to the hills and look for bullet shells with Cyrus, Vanessa, and me. I'll finish the laundry tomorrow while they're at school though.

Document modifications

On 2017-11-02, this journal page was modified in order to redact the name of the university and the link to their website.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Attempting to debug SD card support

Day 00451: Tuesday, 2016 May 31

Wowaname has now banned me from #Network, presumably because of the join/part cycle that my client is going through every ten minutes. No one even says anything in that channel though! The claim that two lines every ten minutes is somehow more disruptive than the walls of Unicode art that the other channel members love to post was bad enough, but now I'm being banned from a channel in which I can't disrupt anyone at all. I'm leaving Volatile, at least until wowaname and I can come to some sort of an understanding. For now, there's no point staying on a network in which I've been banned from the main channel and in which I'm going to end up banned from the other channels one by one.

Josh Woodward sent out a link to the second album promised to Kickstarter backers, though it seems that this album was abandoned and forgotten until recently when Josh remembered that he needed to send it to those that paid for it. They said to keep this album to ourselves for now because they plan to take the songs from the abandoned album and use them elsewhere, though they didn't provide the promised FLAC files, just like with the main album, Addressed to the Stars. Unlike with Addressed to the Stars though, I wasn't able to find the back door link to the FLAC files and there might not even be one. I wrote back to Josh asking about the FLAC files for both albums, so we'll see how they respond.

I tried to debug my mobile a bit again, but it didn't go any better than last time. When I first booted it, it claimed that encryption was "unsuccessful" and that a factory reset would be required. I was worried that the internal storage drive had a few flipped bits or something rendering the device unable to decrypt, but the message provided was likely put there with the intention that if the initial encryption process had failed, the drive data would be unreadable and that message would be displayed. The message also mentioned that any data that wasn't backed up by Google's services would be lost. No doubt this is a remnant of Android's code that Paul, the Replicant developer, had missed due to that mention of Google's services being unseen in most cases and Paul not having the proper team to help them that they deserve. A simple reboot fixed the data issue, though I still didn't manage to get the device to work with Ext4 SD cards. As an experiment, I tried using an SD card with an encrypted file system. In this case, the mobile complains that the SD card is blank or has an unsupported file system. The thing to note here is that it says that the card is unreadable, but does *not* say that the card is damaged. However, every time that I try to use the Ext4 file system, the mobile claims that the SD card is damaged. The mobile also until recently had no problem reading Ext4 SD cards. I pulled out a small pile of SD cards to test with today, and strangely, none of them worked when formatted as Ext4, unlike last time. Before, I managed to get one of my eight gigabyte cards to work, but was unsatisfied because that was too small of a card. Today, I tried two sixteen gigabyte cards, an eight gigabyte card, and a four gigabyte card. None of them worked. I also had a two gigabyte card, but it doesn't seem to work on the laptop, so I really had no way to format it for use on the mobile and didn't even try. Strangely, all of these SD cards that I tried were formatted as FAT before I formatted them for this experimentation. The other day though, I formatted some cards as Ext4 for experimentation that day. Somehow, these aren't the same SD cards from before. Where are my other SD cards? Maybe they'll turn up later and I can settle for the eight gigabyte card that worked before, as I planned to do today. Without working storage, my mobile doesn't function as the music player that I mainly use it for these days.

Lastly, the IRC reconnection cycle that my client has been going through on Volatile is now present on another network, namely, my own. I can now say with relative certainty that the issue is on my end, not Volatile's. I still see no need for me to be banned in a channel that is in favor of and actively encourages frequent flooding, but if I cared about this "problem", I now know to look within my own computer and/or network to find what's going wrong.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.